This one prompt just changed the way
that I create consistent characters with
AI forever. I stress tested this across
a number of complex use cases like
facial tattoos and strange scars as well
as very specific piercings. And the
results were truly incredible. Yet
nearly everyone is still over
complicating the character consistency
process. So, I'm going to show you how
you can lock your character consistency
once and for all using one simple
prompt. Let's take a closer look at
exactly how this works. Now, using one
simple well- definfined prompt, we can
get out this perfect character sheet
which displays to us our character from
each angle. We get the whole body shown
from the front, from the side, from a
three/arter view, and from the back. We
also get the face close up from the
front and from the profile. Now, this
gives us exquisite references to then go
out and make videos just like this.
So, let's do it together. If you want to
follow along with this, I'll leave a
link to all the problems that I'm using
for free in the description below. This
method works across all image models and
platforms. The power is in the
repeatable system. I've already tested
it inside Nanobanana 2, and it's even
stronger. For most of this video, you'll
see me using what was called Nano Banana
Pro. And it's possible for you to use
this either inside of Gemini or where I
prefer to use it, which is in Google
Flow. Now, I prefer flow because it's
specifically designed for visual
creation. Now, we have two options here.
You can even start creating your own
original character inside of Flow or you
can take a reference from somewhere
else. I find the following image model
to have the highest degree of aesthetics
and that is our old favorite midjourney.
So, to show you this, I will be taking a
recent exploration that I created and
I'm going to be working with this woman
here. Now the next step is to upload it
as a image reference. Now you can go
ahead and copy the prompt from the first
page of the prompt guide and pop that
into your prompt bar. Now to give you a
quick summary of what this prompt
entails without reading the entire
thing. It asks us to give a very
specific layout where we are seeing our
protagonist in some very specific poses.
It also outlines exactly what style of
reference sheet that we want. that makes
sure that it's hyperrealistic and it
doesn't fall into creating like a 3D
render style. Now, you can select the
number of outputs. I find four is the
best approach. And the reason for that
is one of the key caveats with working
with AI imagery is that it's very rare
that you get the right output on the
first take. Now, what's incredibly
remarkable about this is just how
visually intelligent Nano Banana is.
Let's take a look at what I mean. We
have this perfect rendering of all of
the elements that we are looking for.
It's exquisitly captured all of the
detail. Now, what you can do, of course,
is upscale this directly inside of Flow.
And to upscale it, all you have to do is
go to download and then select 2K. You
can even get 4K now upscaled if you're
on the highest tier. But it's
interesting to look at the different
variations we get out. And as you can
see, each one has a slightly different
interpretation of what we create. Now,
you'll also notice that sometimes it
doesn't always accurately give us the
head to toe feature. That's one of the
slight bugs of this, but if you go
through a couple of iterations, it will
do. So, the other fix to this is to take
the one that you like and then
explicitly add that as an image prompt
and then say remake this image, ensuring
the entire top row shows full body views
from head to toe. All subject in top row
must be fully visible including feet
with no cropping at the ankles, knees or
head. As you can see, once we add this
prompt and edit it, we get an updated
version with our feet included. Now, to
show you a few examples of just how
powerful this is, especially with some
complex edge cases, take a look at
these. Here we have a animated character
and you can see from the output that
it's possible to get a perfectly
rendered character sheet of this little
crocodile chap as well who's a little
cutie. How can we take this even
further? Well, we can look at adding
extremely unique artifacts to our
characters which are harder to recreate.
For example, scars and tattoos. So, as
you can see, I've created this gentleman
with this very strong scar coming down
the side of his face. And you can see
that across all instances, it is
perfectly consistently rendered. Now,
we've got these wonderful images, but of
course, this is just the start because
what we want to start to do is create
whole sequences of our character. And
there are a couple of approaches that
you can use for this. Now, the first
method is the quickest. And to do that,
what you can do is take your image
reference and in Google Flow and use it
as an ingredient. And to do that, all
you have to do is go to the drop down
and switch to ingredients to video. Now,
other tools do have their own
equivalents of ingredients, too, but
sometimes they name them a little bit
differently just to confuse things. Now,
once you've popped the image in, you can
reference it in the prompt. So, you can
say, "Create a video of this woman
commanding a spaceship." Then you can
select the amount of outputs you want
and go ahead and generate that.
But what I think is the best approach
because it gives us more control is to
first create an image and then use that
as the first frame for our video
creation. That's because we get a bit
more control over exactly what the video
outputs will be. So to do that, it's
extremely simple. All you do again is
switch to create image, insert our
initial character reference as an image
reference, and then create an image
referencing our character. So I've asked
it to show this character riding a
futuristic motorbike through a dark neon
lit city at night. And I will get four
images for this and go ahead and
generate. Now we get our output. All we
have to do is go to frames to video and
we can use this as the first frame of
our video. And I found that this gives
us a much higher quality result. Now the
next fun thing we can do is start to
combine our characters into scenes. So
we might take this young lady and I will
also be working with another character
I've been developing which is myself as
James Bond. Then I can add my myself to
the prompt and we can define the exact
interaction that we would like to see
between our two cast members. So, I've
asked to show these two characters
standing and talking at the edge of a
cinematic bridge. Now, you might be
asking how I get these very long,
detailed, and specific prompts. Well,
for that, I use metaprompting. I take my
initial idea and then ask ChatGBT to
specifically enhance my prompt, and
consistently it gets me better results.
I'll also include that metaprompt inside
of my prompting guide. Here we have me
and this lady talking.
>> You think you can defy me here?
>> We need to reconsider. It's too
dangerous.
>> Failure is not an option.
>> But there's so much more we can do. And
I want to show you some other creative
ways that we can use this method. And
the first is by adjusting the lighting.
So what we can do is we can take our
reference sheet and then use the
lighting prompt from the character sheet
prompt guide. And we can then completely
adjust the lighting. This means that we
get the ability to move between
completely different lighting
situations. We can take this neon lit
situation and use it to reference future
videos. But we can do so much more
because we can also go ahead and change
the outfits of our characters. So I've
taken our female protagonist and I've
outfitted her with some metallic armor.
Now you can also see her in some sort of
imperial loungewear. And to do this,
it's extremely easy. All you have to do
is take the reference sheet, use it as
an image reference, and then the
following prompt. Let's do one together.
You I've taken the reference sheet. I
popped in the prompt. Now, in the
prompt, there is the option to input
your own definition of a outfit, but
what's also cool is that you can use an
image reference as an outfit. So, I'll
be using this red cocktail dress. And
I'll upload that as an image reference.
Crop and save it. And go ahead and
generate. And here we have our
character. And as you can see, she is
wearing this lovely red cocktail dress.
But let's try and push this as far as we
can and see if we can break it. So let's
hypothetically say our character in our
film wants to go ahead and get a complex
face tattoo. So we have our facial
tattoos and we can go ahead and generate
some images and see if we can maintain
this perfectly consistent tattoo with
such a complex use case. Now there's
also another way we can do this which is
simply by not using an image reference
and using a text prompt to define our
character straight away. Now, this cuts
out a stage, but I would say that you
are losing some control with that
approach. But there is a prompt in the
guide to do it that way, too. And as you
can see, you can still get out some
extremely useful results. This could be
perfect if you're looking to create some
marginal characters who only appear
periodically. Now, let's take a close-up
look at how well it's rendered out this
face tattoo. And you can see that it
maintains wonderful consistency. Now,
another extremely impressive way that we
can use this method is by aging our
characters. And this can be incredibly
useful if you're looking to show
flashbacks or flash forwards to
different eras of a charact's life. So,
I thought I would do it on myself and
see how I'm going to look in about 15
years time. Looks as though I'm holding
up pretty well. And to do this, I've
also included a prompt which you can
simply copy and paste, use the character
reference, and then use that prompt. And
all you have to do is change the number
of years. So this is me by 15 years and
here's me by 50 years. We can actually
use these to show fantastic time-lapse
transformations of characters aging. So
here is one example of myself aging from
the current age all the way through to
50 years in the future. And to do that
it's very simple. All we have to do is
generate a first portrait-like frame of
ourselves or a character at one age and
then we can create a second frame of
them at a different age and use those
two as references in image to video. So
all you need to do is go to frames to
video, insert the first frame as the
young version and insert the second
frame as the older version and then you
can use a prompt like uh time-lapse
between these two ages and you get out
this very impressive result. Now, one
thing that this type of character
consistency unlocks is the ability to
create effective digital personas. And I
think this is going to be one of the
hugest trends and biggest opportunities
for making money online with AI. And if
you are interested in that, I'd love to
tell you about today's sponsor. Now, AI
content creation is a huge opportunity,
but let's talk about how we can actually
monetize our AI content. Right now,
content creation with AI is one of the
most interesting emerging business
models. You don't need to show your
face. You don't need to be famous. You
don't need to be a hot girl. You don't
even need a team. You can build an AI
character, generate content at scale,
and grow an audience fast, all with AI.
Now, what's great about this is it's
early, and when you're in early, the
leverage is incredible. This is the
future of content creation, and that's
exactly where Fan View comes in. It's
the first platform built specifically
for AI first influencers. While other
platforms are still debating whether AI
creators are allowed, Van View is fully
embracing them. You can post, grow, and
start earning immediately. It's already
the most AI friendly platform out there
and it's leading the charge. Inside my
AI influencer course, I walk you through
exactly how you create your own AI
character, how to grow it, how to craft
it, and how to launch it in the right
way. And in this course, I specifically
recommend Fan View as the platform to
monetize your character. People are
already making thousands a month doing
this, and the waves only getting bigger,
and it's the ones who start now are the
ones who are going to win. So, be bold
and build your own influencer. Check out
both links in the description below, and
a big thanks to FanView for sponsoring
this segment of the video. Creating
highly consistent characters is the holy
grail for AI film making and now it's
much easier with the ability to use
effective character reference prompts.
We've looked at how you can create your
own reference sheets using this highly
helpful prompt. We've taken a look at
ways that we can change the character's
outfit, change their age, change the
lighting conditions, and also animate
different characters together
consistently. This unlocks a whole new
world of AI film making possibilities.
Download my free prompts in the
description below. And if you enjoyed
this video, then watch this one next,
which is all about some powerful
cinematic film making techniques. And
it's a great place to apply this type of
character consistency. But most of all,
I want to say thank you so much for
watching. I truly appreciate you being
here. And I wish you a delightful